翻译
monica-卡 InX
牌子上写着Richard Gammon
Gammon是一个德国姓氏
三辆德系跑车
Audi R8 2017 ; Mercedes-Benz AMG GT ; Porsche 911 Turbo S
翻译
CC 17 lxbenz
校对
Monica-卡 natas 17 RN
背景为梅赛德斯-奔驰博物馆
时间轴
Monica-卡 natas RN
梅赛德斯-奔驰斯图加特分部
位于斯图加特的保时捷博物馆旧馆
位于斯图加特的保时捷博物馆新馆
谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
非常感谢
Thank you very much. Thank you.
谢谢大家 欢迎来到伟大的旅程
Danke. Danke und willkommen in der Große Tour
本期节目来自德国
which this week comes from Germany!
是的 我们来了
Ja. We're here. We're here.
准确地说 这里是斯图加特
Specifically... Specifically, we are in the city of Stuttgart.
我们差点来不了
Except we nearly weren't.
因为你们当地的一位绿党政治家
Because one of your local Green politicians
试图禁止入境
tried to ban us from coming here.
我不想在节目上让他难堪
I don't want to embarrass the poor man on television.
所以我们隐匿了他的身份
So I've hidden his identity.
没错
Yeah.
-是啊  -这很好
- Yeah. - That's good.
非常恰当
That's appropriate.
我肯定不会告诉你们他的名字
I certainly don't want to tell you his name.
就是Andreas Kasdorf(德国绿党成员)
Which is... Andreas Kasdorf.
不太受欢迎啊 但你们投票选了他
Not a popular man. But you elected him.
总之 他说不欢迎我们来这儿
Anyway, he says that we'd be unwelcome here
因为这是个自行车友好城市
because this is a very bicycle-friendly place.
才怪 这是奔驰和保时捷的家乡
It... It isn't. It's the home of Mercedes and Porsche.
-德国还是  -正是
- And Germany... - Exactly.
德国
Germany...
德国是汽车工业的摇篮
Germany is the cradle of the automobile.
汽车就是在这发明的
The car was actually invented here.
这是地球上唯一一个地方
It's the last place on Earth you can drive a car
你能在高速上开到极速
as fast as it will go on the motorway.
-实话  -大实话
- It's true. - All true.
这是铁打的事实
This is a true fact. This is a true fact.
德国人是唯一
The Germans are the only people on Earth
真正知道如何造车的人
who really know how to make a car.
这是
This is...
-这是不争的事实  -对
- It's a true fact. - It's true.
给你们讲个故事
I'll tell you a story.
某晚 一个奔驰工程师
There was a Mercedes engineer
和一个捷豹工程师吃饭
and a Jaguar engineer having dinner one night.
奔驰工程师说 俺们有
The Mercedes engineer said, "Ve haf..."
原谅我的口音(模仿德国口音)
Forgive the accent.
奔驰车间里有个质量测试
"Ve haf a quality test at ze Mercedes factory.
每晚 我们随机挑一辆生产线上的车
Every night, ve take a car off ze line at random.
在里面放只猫 关上门
Ve put a cat in it, close ze doors.
如果早上我们回来的时候
If... When ve come back in ze morning,
猫闷死了
ve know the door seals are vorking correctly
就能确定车门密封性很好
if ze cat has suffocated."
不
Nah.
捷豹工程师说
The Jaguar engineer said,
我们车间也有类似的测试
"We've got something very similar at our factory.
先从流水线上挑一辆车
We take a car off the line at random.
放只猫进去 关上车门
We put a cat in it. We close the door.
如果隔天早上看到猫还在
And we know the car's been built properly
我们就知道车质量合格了
if, when we come back in the morning, the cat hasn't escaped.
真事
That is...
-真事  -对的
- True story. - Yeah. True story.
奇怪的是
The strange thing is,
这不仅车造得好
it isn't just cars that are built well here.
-一切都很好  -除了红酒
- It's absolutely everything. - Except wine.
对 不好意思 除了红酒
Yes, except wine. Sorry.
不是吧
Well, come on!
-拜托  -你们喝那玩意儿吗
- Now come on! - You drink that stuff?
拿来洗头我都嫌弃
I wouldn't wash my hair in it.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
真的是所有工艺都精湛
It is literally everything, though.
德国毛绒玩具
German soft toys,
最好的毛绒玩具
better than anybody else's soft toys.
照相机 厨房用具
Cameras, kitchen appliances.
英国女皇 她也是德国产的
The Queen of England, she's German.
真的 这就是为什么
She is. That's why she's still working
她都157岁了还没罢工
even though she's a hundred and forty seventeen years old.
这儿的字典没有"还行"二字
There is no word here for "that'll do".
在德国没有模棱两可的说法
There is no ambiguity at all in Germany.
从电影名中就看出来
You certainly see this with films.
你们给美国电影起的名字
The names you have for American films.
我这有一些 记得Airplane这部电影吗
I've got some here. Remember Airplane?
Airplane 记得(1980年美国电影 中文译名"空前绝后满天飞")
Airplane, yes.
在德国 它叫做
In Germany, it was called
失控飞机中的不思议之旅
The Unbelievable Journey In The Crazy Airplane.
这个标题很直观
That is a comprehensive title.
一看就知道内容是什么
You know where you are with that.
大白鲨在这叫什么
What was Jaws?
什么 白色的
The what? The Weiße...?
白色的鲨鱼
The White Shark.
应该叫巨型鲨鱼
It should have been The Massive Shark...
最终炸了
...That Explodes Eventually.
一看也知道在讲什么
You know where you're going with that.
本能的译名呢
What was... What was Basic Instinct?
难道不是
Just not
莎朗·斯通私处的匆匆一瞥吗
A Brief Glimpse Of Sharon Stone's Vagina?
-我们能继续节目吗  -好主意
- Shall we get on with the show? - Yes, good idea.
在今晚的汽车节目中
Because in tonight's car programme...
理查德遛了条狗
Richard walks a dog.
詹姆斯在健身房晃悠
James hangs around a gym.
我说了好枪法
And I say "Good shot."
好枪法
Good shot.
但在那之前 我想谈一下
But before all that, I'd like to talk
初代本田NSX
about the original Honda NSX.
这里有张照片
We have a picture of it here.
1990年推出这车时
When that car was launched in 1990,
简直令人惊叹
it was considered remarkable
因为它和法拉利一样快 一样刺激
because it was fast and exciting like a Ferrari,
但又和当时的法拉利不同
but unlike a Ferrari of the time,
它质量极其可靠
it was also incredibly reliable
操控性非常之好
and very, very easy to drive.
12年前本田砍掉了这款车型
Honda killed that car off 12 years ago.
但最终 他们推出了替代品
But finally, they've come up with a replacement.
所以我到了我们的赛道上一探究竟
So I've been down to our track to see what it's like.
就是它了
This is it.
价值13.8万
It costs £138,000.
和保时捷911 turbo S差不多
Around the same as a Porsche 911 Turbo S.
线条极富未来感
And it has the futuristic lines
正是你在限量版本田上想看到的
you would expect of a rare-breed Honda.
动力来源于3.5升双涡轮增压V6
Power comes from a 3.5 litre twin-turbo V6.
并备有一系列电动机
Backed up by a squadron of electric motors.
它们一起提供了573匹马力
Together, they give the NSX 573 horsepower.
所以你会猜想这车的性能
So you would assume the performance
应该不愧于此
is something to shout about.
如果你向本田询问
Now, if you ask Honda
这车的技术参数
for the technical information on this car,
他们会发给你一封巨型邮件
they will email you a file so enormous
大到互联网都无法承载
that it actually breaks the internet.
然而 内容却从未提及百公里加速时间
And yet, nowhere in it does it mention the 0-60 time.
他们就是拒绝透露
They simply refuse to tell us what it is.
我知道现实中 百公里加速时间无关紧要
I know 0-60 times are irrelevant in the real world
并且十分幼稚 但这是辆超级跑车
and they're rather childish, but look, this is a supercar.
它赢在极速上 这才是关键
It's top trumps, isn't it? It's important.
所以我要用这个帮你们测出来
So I'm gonna find out what it is for you using this.
这是个数据记录仪
It is a data-o-logger.
进入赛道模式
Right. Put it in Track mode.
走着 弹射起步
Here we go. Launch control.
左脚刹车 右脚油门到底
Foot on the brake. Mash the pedal.
我不确定这像GTR那样
I'm not sure that was quite as neck-snapping
快得脖子都要扯断
as a Nissan GTR,
但也差不多了
but it wasn't far off.
来看看结果如何
Let's see what I did.
百公里加速3.2秒
3.2 seconds 0-60.
所以这不如迈凯伦570S那么快
Which means it isn't quite as fast as a McLaren 570S,
也不如911 turbo S
or a 911 Turbo S,
或者法拉利488 GTB
or a Ferrari 488 GTB.
怪不得他们不肯说
That's why they're not mentioning it.
本田倒是很乐意提及它的极速
Honda is happy to quote the top speed.
高达每小时307公里
Which is 191 miles an hour.
但依然比它的竞争对手慢
But that too is slower than its rivals
如法拉利 保时捷 迈凯伦
from Ferrari, Porsche, and McLaren.
所以新款NSX
So has the new NSX got anything
在性能上有哪点
in the performance department
比同级跑车更好呢
that makes it rise above its supercar peers?
还真有
Well, yes, actually.
首先 它的电子刹车
Firstly, there are the brakes, which are fly-by-wire.
刹车和踏板间没有物理连接
There is no physical connection to the pedal.
因为它们要把刹车能量回收
That's because they have to harvest energy
返还到电池系统
to recharge the battery system.
这比保时捷918的版本
It's a much cleverer version of that
要先进得多
than you get on the Porsche 918,
918还要贵5倍
a car that costs five times as much.
然后 混动系统
Then there's the hybrid system.
不止是一个电机
It uses not one electric motor,
它用了三个
as you might expect, but three.
使用方式也是别出心裁
And the way it uses them is well good.
后面的电机
The one at the back
是汽油机的僚机
is the wingman for the petrol engine,
涡轮迟滞时 能填补动力缺失
filling the power gaps when the turbos lag.
这让NSX在任何速度下都能如出膛般加速
This gives the NSX ballistic pick-up at any speed.
看 瞬间的推力 太美妙了
Look, instant shove. It's lovely.
但前面的两个电机才是真的主角
But it's the two at the front that are the real party-piece
因为它们完全独立地
because they drive a wheel
驱动两边的轮子
each totally independently of each other.
这意味着它有着
Which means this car has
和宇宙飞船一样先进的四驱系统
a sort of space-age four-wheel drive.
所以在入弯时
And that means extraordinary things happen
也就带来了不可思议的表现
when you throw it into a corner.
比如你接近这个弯角时
So, as you approach a corner like this one,
车载电脑会计算车速
computers are measuring the speed,
检测G力 转向角 等等
they're measuring G-force, steering input, and so forth.
它会根据需要 配给车轮额外的动力
They're adding power to the wheel
或减少部分动力
or taking power away from the wheel as it's needed.
然后你就能平稳 可控地过弯
Then you get perfectly flat, perfectly controlled corners.
有点像开本田思域
It is a bit like driving a Honda Civic!
有人会说
There are people who would say
给车配备了这样的科技
that technology like this in a car,
让它变得更安全也更无趣了
helping it feel secure, will make it dull.
但我并不觉得无趣
But it doesn't feel dull to me.
只觉得惊艳
It feels tremendous.
我能轻松地高速行驶
I'm going fast and I'm relaxing.
这有什么不好
What's wrong with that?
但这个未来感十足的四轮驱动
But the futuristic four-wheel drive
不是NSX上唯一
isn't the only piece of 23rd-century engineering
来自23世纪的产物
on the NSX.
气动特性就非常巧妙
The aerodynamics, for example, are so clever,
它可以冷却所有的电机
they can cool all the motors
同时还能提供大量下压力
while providing vast amounts of grip-enhancing downforce
增加前后轮的抓地力
to the front and rear wheels.
无需传统的尾翼和扰流板
And it does all this without anything
它就能做到这些
as old-fashioned as huge wings and spoilers.
不仅是因为这些激动人心的科技
It's not just the technology, which is brilliant,
而是这些科技都与车融为一体
it's that that technology is on this car
没错 我们有混动超跑
Yes, we have hybrid supercars.
我们有LaFerrari 迈凯伦P1
We have the LaFerrari, the McLaren P1,
保时捷918
the Porsche 918.
但是这些都要数百万
But they're in the million-pound bracket.
NSX的价格只有LaFerrari的八分之一
This is only an eighth of the price of the LaFerrari,
且NSX的设计更精妙
and it's actually cleverer.
我爱这辆车
I love this.
我爱它的外观 我爱它的声音
I love the way it looks. I love the sounds it makes.
我喜欢这复杂精巧的混动系统
I like the sophistication of the hybrid drive.
我喜欢它的性能
I like the performance.
我喜欢它的转向操控 还有这内饰
I like the steering. I like the interior.
我真的很喜欢它
I really, really like it.
我发现自己按捺不住地想入手一辆
And I find myself wanting one quite badly.
初代NSX让人们可以
The original NSX made owning a supercar
用低廉的价格拥有一辆舒适的超跑
less painful and less expensive.
这代混动超跑也一样
This has done the same for the hybrid supercar.
它的确是名合格的继承者
It really is a worthy successor.
詹姆斯 本田
James, Honda...
本田花了十年时间研发这车
Honda took ten years to develop that car.
然后呢
And?
造辆车 用十年
Ten years is an enormous amount of time
太过了
to do a car.
你不能因为花的时间太长
You can't criticise something
就批评它
because people spent too long on it.
没人会说 我不去参观科隆大教堂
People aren't gonna say "I'm not gonna look round Cologne cathedral.
这花了600年才建好"
They took 600 years to build it!"
总之 我爱这辆车
Anyway, I love it. I love that car.
不管怎样 我们已经听完
Anyway, look, we've heard
你对NSX的评价了
what you've got to say about the NSX.
现在要把它移交给这个人
Now it's time to hand it over
他觉得
to a man who thinks that...
盆栽植物是共产主义的阴谋
Well, potted plants are a Communist plot.
没错 有请老美
Yep. Here he comes. It's the American!
英国 天气糟心 啤酒糟心
Come to England. Shit weather. Shit beer.
他出发了
And he's off!
明显兴致高昂
Clearly in a tremendous mood.
但路面非常潮湿
But it is very wet out there.
他一脚油门进入不直道时
Wipers flapping away
雨刮在狂甩
as he powers onto the Isn't Straight.
看起来不错
Looking good.
在我老家
Where I come from,
这玩意儿的标志就是"不精准" (ACURA原意"精准")
this thing's badge is inaccurate.
有点像屌丝才开的凯迪拉克
Kind of like a loser's Cadillac.
奇怪的是 我们还在等
And yet, strangely, we're still waiting
凯迪拉克的混动超跑上市
for Cadillac's hybrid supercar.
现在 飞驰进入留你名弯
Right, now, flying into Your Name Here,
今天真适合开四驱车
this really is a good day to have four-wheel drive.
我相信就算是老美
I'm sure even the American can appreciate
也会赞赏本田的高科技
the Honda's hi-tech features.
这是啥外太空玩意
What is this Space Invaders shit?
当我没说
Clearly not.
地板油再次通过不直道
Right, full power for the Isn't again.
电不该用在引擎上 那是给车灯和座椅用的
Electric ain't for engines. It's for lights and chairs.
他确实有点落伍
He is not a modern man, is he?
好的 划过一片水潭
Right, carving through the standing water.
进入老奶房弯
Into Old Lady's House.
略微有点滑
Slithering about a bit.
现在他飞速驶过颠簸路段
Now he's leaning on it for the Unsettled section.
过了机库 到了变电箱弯
Past the hangars and up to Sub Station.
大力猛踩电子刹车
Hard on those wi-fi brakes
减速过倒数第二个弯
for the second-to-last corner.
这里他要怎么过呢
How's he gonna manage through here?
是的 走线靠外 略微动力不足
Yes, stepping out a bit under power.
通过绵羊坡
Through Field Of Sheep,
走线很紧 穿过终点
keeping it tidy through there, and across the line!
好的
Right,
看看NSX在圈速榜上排名如何
let's see now where the NSX goes on our lap board.
我们来看看
Let's have a look.
我的天 詹姆斯
Oh, dear, James.
詹姆斯
James.
你怎么不告诉我们它这么慢
Why didn't you tell us it was very slow?
-这是因为跑道太湿了  -等等
- It's streaming wet! - So hang on a minute.
来自乌龟的测评加上湿圈速
We've had a review from a tortoise and a wet lap.
所以这都是白费功夫了
Which means we've learnt precisely nothing.
恩 是的
Um... Yeah, you're right. Nothing at all.
-白费功夫了  -好的我们继续
- Nothing at all. - So let's move on.
好 让我们往售票机里投币
Yes, let's do that by popping some loose change in the ticket machine
在唠嗑街上停会儿车
so we can park awhile on Conversation Street.
现在
OK, now...
-我有话要说  -很好
- I've got some conversation. - Good.
昨天半夜 斯图加特有天气警报
Last night at midnight, there was alarm in Stuttgart.
当地的执政党 绿党
The Green Party that runs the city
建议居民不要使用烧柴的炉子
asked everyone here not to use wood-burning stoves
并且今天不要开车
and not to drive their car today.
-为什么  -因为雾霾
- Why? - Because of the smog.
我是瞎编的吗
Am I making this up?
证据在这
There it is.
没有什么
I can't...
比这更清楚了
I can't imagine anything clearer.
这空气透亮的和琴酒一样
That is... That is gin-clear,
但是据绿党所说
but according to the Green Party...
我真没瞎说
I'm not making this up.
你们都是斯图加特人 对吧
You're all from Stuttgart, yes?
今天的天气报警
There is an alarm today
-是因为雾霾吧  -是的
- because of the smog. - Yes.
在哪儿呢
Where is it?
天气好的时候 还能更透亮吗
How clear is it on a good day?
这有张北京的照片
We've got a photograph here of Beijing on now.
我们来对比一下
Let us compare and contrast
北京的雾霾天和斯图加特的
Beijing on a smoggy day with Stuttgart on a...
-不一样吧  -雾霾天
- Not the same. - ...a smoggy day.
我就问一下 如果绿党真的禁止开车
Can I just ask, what would you have done
你们要怎么做
if they'd have actually ordered you not to drive cars?
现在这只是个倡议
At the moment, it's an advisory.
如果他们说禁止开车
If they said you are banned from driving cars,
你们怎么办
what would you have done?
乘火车过来 无法想象
Come on the train? That's unbelievable.
但事实是
But this is the thing
我们不懂德国人
that we don't really understand about Germany.
规矩就是规矩
Once something becomes a rule, it is a rule.
有一次我和两个朋友
I once had a very interesting conversation
进行了一次有趣的交谈
with two friends of mine.
一个是加州来的 另一个是德国人
One is from California and one is from Germany.
我们在讨论 驾照丢了怎么办
We were talking about losing your driving licence.
加州人问 在德国 如果驾照丢了
The Californian said, "In Germany, what would happen
开车会怎样
if you lost your licence and then you drove your car?"
德国人说 不 你不能这么做
The German said, "No, you cannot do this."
他说 这不应该
He says, "I know you're not supposed to,
但假如你开了呢
but what if you did?"
德国人说 不 你不能开 你没驾照
He said, "No. You cannot drive. You have no licence."
加州人说 我知道
The Californian went, "Yeah, man,
但某天晚上 你就是
but late one night, you just...
控制不住地开了车
hell, you go for a drive."
德国人说
The German went, "It is impossible
没有驾照就不可能开车
to drive without a licence!"
-不可能  -不可能
- Impossible! - Impossible.
我发现了一件有趣的事
There's an interesting thing I discovered here.
在高速上 你想开多快都行
On a motorway, obviously you can drive as fast as you like.
但就有人 虽然不常见
You get people sometimes, not often,
因为你们的变线纪律太严格了
cos your lane discipline is unbelievable,
但就有人在快车道上慢吞吞地爬
but sometimes they sit in the outside lane just dawdling.
如果你在后面跟车 我这有处罚条例
If you tailgate them... OK? I've got the fines here.
你要付400欧的罚款 记2分
You get a 400 euro fine, two penalty points,
并且三个月内禁止跟车
and a three-month ban for tailgating.
-这真是极刑啊 太狠了  -是的
- That is extreme. Ouch! - Yes.
但如果你从内侧超车
But if you overtake them on the inside,
从内车道上超过他们
just go past them on the inside,
就是150欧罚款 记1分
that's a 150 euro fine, and one point.
这个不错
Well, there you go.
等等 高潮来了
No. This is where it gets really good.
如果你从路肩超车 也就是紧急停车带
If you go on the hard shoulder to overtake, the emergency lane,
也是记1分 但是只有90欧罚款
that's also one point but only a 90 euro fine.
找到正解了 就这么办
There's your answer. That's what you do!
不行
No, no.
等等 你以为这就完了吗
No, because... Aha. You may think that.
如果你给车装上蓝色的灯
But if you fit your car with blue lights,
那种蓝色的闪灯
flashing blue lights, basically,
你基本就把车改成了警车
you turn you car into a police car,
让我看看处罚条例
you get... I've got the point fines here.
你将罚款20欧 不记分
20 euro fine and no points at all!
你在逗我吗
What? You're joking!
-你不懂  -这是真的
- No, you don't understand. - That is true.
这听上去不合理
That is very strange to our ears.
因为如果你在英国这么干的话
Cos if you tried that at home in the UK,
你将被控 假扮警察
you would be charged with impersonating a police officer,
你这辈子都别想从监狱里出来了
and you would never get out of prison, ever.
人们常说德国人缺乏幽默细胞
People say Germans have no sense of humour.
如果你想知道什么叫不幽默
If you want to know what no sense of humour is,
来英国 假扮个警察试试
impersonate a policeman in Britain.
你就知道什么叫做一点也不幽默了
Then you'll know what no sense of humour is.
好啦 我们今天的唠嗑街就到这里了
Right, that is the end of Conversation Straße.
我们都喜欢 SUV 的概念
We all like the idea of a sports utility vehicle.
一台车 在周末 足够应付澳大利亚内陆沙漠
A car that can handle the Australian outback at the weekend
在周一早上 又能去霍根海姆赛道上刷个新的最快圈速
and then set a new lap record at Hockenheim on a Monday morning.
但是就连德国的车厂
But even the German car-makers
好想都不能把这个概念玩顺溜
can't seem to make the concept work.
这是奥迪的产品 RS Q3
We've got this from Audi. The RS Q3.
车不怎么样
Which is a dismal car.
宝马也推出了X4 我记得是这个名字
BMW have the X4, I think that's called.
但是我哪个都不喜欢
Don't want one of those, either.
奔驰也有这个吓人的大魔头
Mercedes have this horrible monster.
他们都很垃圾
They're all just rubbish.
让我猜猜 你有个办法
And let me guess. You have a solution.
-可不是么 -天啊
- Yes, I do. - Oh, God.
我当然有了 有那么一台车
Yes, I do. A car
应该既运动又多功能
that is both sporty and utilitarian.
这下好看了
This will be good.
你心一点都不诚 看好了
Ye of little faith. Watch this.
这是一台路虎发现
This is a Land Rover Discovery
在英国泥泞的南部
doing utilitarian things
做着功能性的事情
in Britain's muddy underbelly.
一台像这样的机器 很明显
And obviously a machine like this
不可能被改造成一台跑车
cannot possibly be converted into a sports car.
真的么
Or can it?
首先 你得把这非常丑的车身拆下来
First of all, we have to remove this rather ungainly body.
但是现代的汽车你就没法这么拆
You can't do that with a modern car
因为车身本身就是底盘 是承力的骨架
because the body is the chassis. It's the skeleton.
如果你把底盘卸了 你除了一堆没法装上去的配件外
If you take it away, you're left with nothing more
什么都没有了
than a collection of unjoined-up parts.
然而 你可以把车身像这样
However, you can remove the body
从一台发现上卸下来
on an old Discovery like this,
用的工具不会比这更多了
using nothing more than one of these.
仅仅过了40分钟
After just 40 minutes
在没人帮忙的情况下
with no help from anyone else,
我把车变成了这样
I ended up with this.
很显然 它依然是多功能的
Obviously it's still utilitarian.
它依然可以趟过河流
It will still wade through rivers
并且缓缓爬上泥泞的河岸
and crawl its way up muddy banks.
但是现在
But now there's a...
开始有了丝丝运动的味道
a sporty flavour as well.
在移除了沉重的车身后 它开起来灵活敏捷又轻盈
Without the heavy body, it feels nimble, agile, light.
要不是风挡是那么接近我的脸
If it weren't for the fact that the windscreen is now very close to my face,
我都会以为这是一台兰博基尼盖拉多
it would feel like a Lamborghini Gallardo.
这东西真正的问题在于
The only real problem with this
英国是一个受警察管制的国家
is that Britain is a police state,
如果我开着这玩意儿上路
and if I took this on a public road,
我马上就会被警察截停
I'd be stopped immediately
警察会告诉我
by the constabulary who would point out
我将会违反大概
that I was contravening about...
4870条不同的法条
4,870 different laws.
当然 也不暖和
It's not warm, either.
哦 不 这太蠢了
Oh, no, that's stupid!
让人欣慰的是 把它移植上一个跑车的车身
Happily, both these problems would be solved
这些问题都可以解决
when I fitted it with the body from a sports car.
这就是我要找的跑车
And this is the sports car I've gone for.
一台1978年的MGB
A 1978 MGB.
手法熟练的技师开始剥去她的肌肤
Highly-trained men are now removing its skin
并在稍后 通过一场两小时的复杂手术
which will then be mated
将其覆于
in a delicate two-hour operation...
那台充满泥土气息的
...to the internal organs
V8发现的内部器官之上
of the mud-plugging V8.
第二天早上
The following morning
我无与伦比的车已经准备好了
my incredible car was ready.
这车简直美极了
It is incredible
就在公棚里 我造就了这样的一台机器
that in a shed I have created something which has...
破解了汽车业界中 车型该如何跨界混合的谜题
eluded the combined might of the motor industry.
这是一台真正的 SUV
It is a proper sports utility vehicle.
我许之以 MGD 之名
I call it the MGD,
现在我就要看看
and now I'm going to find out
它在路上的表现如何
how well it works on a road.
太棒了
This is... magnificent.
这家伙太快了
And it is quick. Oh, yeah.
为了展示其速度
To demonstrate just how quick,
我将来场加速赛
I'm going to do a drag race
对抗汽车行业所设计的SUV
against the motor industry's idea of an SUV.
方向盘有点虚位
Little bit of play there.
开始吧
Let's do this.
走起 看啊
Come on! Yes, look at this.
这1.5升的柴油车
The 1.5-litre diesel
无法和3.9升 V8的MGD媲美
is no match for the 3.9-litre V8 MGD.
加把劲 大英帝国的骄傲
Come on, Pride of Britain!
赢啦
Yes! Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha.
不好
Oh, God.
刹车失灵了
The brakes don't work.
在确信性能表现优异后
With the performance box ticked,
我继续测评
I continued my testing.
MGD在很多方面都让我想起
In many ways, the MGD puts me in mind
奥迪R8敞篷版
of an Audi R8 Spyder.
当然 奥迪的仪表盘肯定不会出问题
I mean, OK, in the Audi, the dials would work.
以及开关 刹车
And the  switches. And the brakes.
还有转向
And the steering.
而且不会这么抖 但是
And it's a bit less bouncy, but...
这俩车
both of them
都是四驱两座
are four-wheel-drive, two-seater,
敞篷的V8
drop-head V8s.
当然 这两者
There is, however, one very big difference
也有一点迥然不同
between the two cars.
开奥迪可干不了这事
You can't do this in an Audi.
太棒了
Oh, yes. Yes.
不久之前 我还在跑道上驰骋
Moments ago I was haring round a handling track,
看如今
and now look.
简直惊为天人
It's brilliant.
别现在罢工啊 这个小崽子
Oh, no! Not now, you bastard.
不对 这个小冤家
I mean, you wonderful thing.
阻风门出问题了
Choke. Oh.
完蛋
Yeah, that...
它苟延残喘了
It's on its shutdown thing.
为了省油
It's just to save fuel,
它偶尔只用两缸工作
it goes on two cylinders sometimes.
等引擎管理的玩意
Once the engine management thingy had run its...
完成诊断程序后
diagnostic program,
我再次出发
I was back on the move.
走着
Here we go.
没错
Yes.
强大的四驱系统把我送上那的
Mighty four-wheel-drive system hauling me up that.
什么鬼
What the hell?
赶紧停车
I'm stopping. Stopping.
天 这看来不太对劲呢
Oh, Lord, that is not right, is it?
再次发动后
As I got going for the second time,
我被自己蠢到了
I realised I'd been a bit of a chump.
我的错误在于
The mistake I've made, of course,
在向你们介绍这车前
is that I've introduced you to this car
我并未真的路测过
before I've really tested it.
汽车制造商可不能这样
That's not what car-makers do.
他们一般先试车
They test a car and then show it
再向媒体和大众展示
to the press and the public.
我本末倒置了
I'm doing that the other way round.
我没测试
I'm introducing this to you
就向你们介绍这车了
before I've done the testing and...
我的天
Oh, for Christ's sake.
你个磨人的小妖精
You little beauty.
刚说到哪了
Er, now, yes, what was I saying?
问题在于 你们在看的是我的工作过程
I think the issue is really you're watching my workings-out here.
而你们真正想看的是成品
What you really want to see is the finished product.
我应该给你们看成品
That's what I should have done.
天
Oh, Christ's sake.
好吧
Right.
至此 毫无由来的 我决定
At this point, I decided, for no particular reason,
打消MG这个主意
to scrap the MG idea
另找别的灵感
and go for something else instead.
这就是我的选择
This is what I chose.
1980年款奔驰SL
A 1980s Mercedes SL.
从一定程度上 它是
Partly because it's the very essence
安静 城市需求
of quiet, urban restraint,
品味与优雅的精髓
taste and elegance.
它是鲍比尤因在达拉斯开的车
It's a car that was driven by Bobby Ewing in Dallas.
主要地 我选它因为
Mostly, though, I chose it because
它与路虎发现的底盘能更好契合
it would fit more snugly on the Discovery chassis.
这个时候 这个孜孜不倦工作了
This time, the men worked tirelessly
将近一天的男人们
for nearly a whole day
来合璧这两辆车
to marry the two cars
而结果十分惊人
and the result was spectacular.
这是一辆车让我无可非议地给它命名为
It's a car I have justifiably called...
卓越
The Excellent.
它的脏腑来自于路虎发现
The internal organs from a Landrover Discovery
套上了迷人的奔驰SL美丽的皮囊
mated to the beautiful skin of a glamorous Mercedes SL.
来创造一个纯粹的版本
To create a vision of pure...
那个词是什么来着
What's the word?
-垃圾 -这才不是垃圾
- Rubbish. - It's not rubbish.
你用刷子还是水桶给它涂的漆
Did you paint it with a brush or a bucket?
它的头灯在你拐弯的时候还会转
It's got those headlights that swivel when you go round a bend.
所以他们指着路
So they point at the road.
好 让我这样问你
OK, let me ask you this.
你更想要哪个
Which would you rather have?
卓越还是保时捷
The Excellent or that Porsche?
-那台保时捷 -为什么
- That Porsche. - Why?
因为它在每个方面都比较好
Because it's better in every single way.
为了证明我那些冷嘲热讽的同事们是错的
To prove my cynical colleagues wrong,
我邀请他们来兜一圈
I invited them to go for a drive.
哦不错
Oh, kind.
看到了没 这是一个为矮个子男士提供的选件
See? It's an optional extra for the shorter gentleman.
-你舒服吗 哈蒙德 -不
- Are you comfy, Hammond? - No.
-我就只能坐进去这么一点吗  -是的
- Is this as in as I can get? - Yep.
好 听这个
Right, listen to this.
哦不 它开了
Oh, no, it moves!
我们只开了几公里 哈蒙德和船长
We'd only gone a few miles before Richard and James
就彻底改变了主意
completely changed their minds
然后意识到 卓越是他们坐过
and realised that The Excellent was the best car
最好的车
they'd ever been in.
不 我们才没有 别在画外音里
No, we haven't. Stop saying things
说些子虚乌有的事情
in voiceover that aren't true.
我还以为你改变主意了
I thought you'd changed your mind.
不 也许有一点 这比我想的还要差
No! Maybe a bit. It's worse than I thought.
-我能把加热器打开吗 -那个还没有连上
- Can I put the heater on? - That's not connected.
-它没有 -没有
- Is it not? - No.
-下面那个刻度盘是什么 -车速表
- What's that dial down there? - Speedometer.
为什么你要用这个 不用那个
Why have you got that one, not that one?
-那个用不了 -它有油量表吗
- That doesn't work. - Has it got a fuel gauge?
-没有那些 -它有温度计吗
- Not as such. - Has it got a temperature gauge?
并没有
Not really.
有这么多线露在外面
There's a lot of wires hanging out of the dash
它们都没有连接东西
that aren't connected to things.
你都没有给它内饰
You haven't given it an interior.
-我可以看到路 -我也能
- I can see the road. - I can as well.
不 地板上有个洞
No, there's a hole in the floor.
让哈蒙德和梅在纠结些细枝末节的问题时
While Hammond and May had one or two minor issues,
它们都同意 如果我把我的车投产
they both agreed that if I were to put my car into production,
它会让我大赚一笔
it would make me a fortune.
不 我们也没有同意那个
No, we didn't agree to that, either.
看 我做了一点算是 说真的
Look, I've done the maths. Honestly.
发现要2500英镑
The Discovery was £2,500.
奔驰要4500英镑 改造要7000英镑
Mercedes £4,500. £7,000 for the work.
一共是14000英镑 -我可以以120000英镑的价钱把它卖了
That's 14,000 quid. I could sell this for £120,000.
-不 你做不到  -我可以做到
- No, you couldn't. - Yes, I could.
卡宴turbo是120
A Cayenne Turbo is 120.
卡宴turbo是保时捷打造的好车
A Cayenne Turbo is a proper car built by Porsche.
这只是一个蠢货把两辆废车拼在一起
This is two scrap cars glued together by a Muppet.
它不是为你这种人设计的
It isn't designed for people like you.
什么人 有眼睛的人
What, people with eyes?
可以早上自己穿衣服的人
People who can dress themselves in the morning?
我会明确的告诉你谁会买这个车
I'll tell you exactly who will buy this car.
用圆尾剪刀的人
People who use roundy-ended scissors.
足球选手
Footballers.
-他们不会 -球员们喜欢法拉利
- No, they won't. - Footballers like Ferraris.
是的 还有宾利和路虎
Yeah, and Bentleys and Range Rovers.
-还有阿斯顿马丁 -才不是这个东西
- And Aston Martins. - Not this thing.
为了证明他们还是错的
To prove them wrong again,
我决定前往这附近的切尔西训练场
I decided to head for the nearby Chelsea training ground.
这些才是懂车的人 不像你们两个
These are people who understand cars, not like you two.
是的 他们懂车 所以他们才会买
Yeah, they understand cars, that's why they buy
路虎和阿斯顿马丁
Range Rovers and Aston Martins.
他们会买这些
They buy those things
是因为他们不知道还有这辆车
cos they didn't know that you could do this.
-我喜欢我的车 -它是坨屎
- I like my car. - It's shit.
他们会侧目的 不是吗
They're flocking to it, aren't they?
-你就等着瞧 -你介意
- You just watch. - Do you mind
我走开站在别人边上吗
if I go and stand next to something else?
很快一下球员来了
Soon some players arrived,
给了理查德和船长一个机会
which gave Richard and James a chance
来炫耀他们的足球知识
to show off their footballing knowledge.
你好高 你应该是个得分手
You're really tall. You should play in goal.
是的 我是个得分手
Yeah, I do, I play in goal.
-我是个守门员  -我就知道
- I'm the goalkeeper. - I know that.
你来自切尔西的哪个区
What part of Chelsea are you from?
-我来自比利时 -噢
- I'm from Belgium. - Oh.
你怎么知道他们是球员
How do you know they're footballers?
好吧 你们难道没有认出他们吗
Well, do you not recognise them?
他们穿着球衣
They're in football outfits.
他没有认出你
He doesn't recognise you.
亚历克斯·弗格森 在哪里
Where's... Where's Alex Ferguson?
为什么我们问他
Why don't we ask him?
这个时候我甩下了我无知的同事们
At this point I dismissed my ignorant colleagues
所以我可以自己操作字幕机
so that I could operate the subtitle machine.
首先 这是在伦敦
明天第一件事
伦敦很冷
我就处理掉我所有车
敞篷 开玩笑
买辆这个
这车看着
对我来说简直完美
舒适性不行啊
头部空间巨大
-你会顶球吗 -可以
- Can you do keepy-uppy? - Yeah.
踢给我个球
Take a shot at me.
这太荒唐了 这个我能怎么办呢
Well, that's ridiculous. What can I do with that?
你应该跳起来
You're supposed to jump.
我觉得它
我觉得这个 可怕至极
I think it is flipping horrific.
太棒了
所以你屠杀了一辆老爷车
So you've butchered a classic car?
你造了辆极佳的SUV
好了 看这个 轻轻投掷
Right, watch this. Little toss...
不
No.
你需要想一想
You need to think of...
这个啊
完全没考虑舒适性吧
才是我所称的好手艺
这门不会掉吧
这门 让劳斯莱斯都羞愧了
这里的葡语
你知道我怎么想么
实在听不懂了
12万英镑太便宜了
-哦 -拦住了
- Ow. - Saved.
我想用每个进球 每个奖杯
来换这辆车
在得出了
Having established
所有顶级的职业球员都喜欢我的车之后
that all top professional footballers loved my car,
我们又重新上路了
we got back on the road.
你拿到任何订单了吗
Did you get any orders?
我发下那个停车场
I noticed that the car park
停满了奔驰G系
was still full of Mercedes G-Class.
-我看到了 -听着
- I saw that. - Listen.
我可以把它拿去拍卖
I could put this into an auction,
最奢侈的 最高档的那种
one of those posh, up-market ones,
它还是可以卖到12万英镑的
and it would sell for £120,000.
它不能
It would not!
为了再次证明他们是错的
To prove them wrong again...
先生们 人们在检查
Gentlemen, people are examining...
是的 他们是主办方
Yeah, they are the organisers.
他们在疑惑自己的地毯
They're wondering about their carpet.
由著名英国工作室手工打造
"Handcrafted by a renowned British atelier...
悲天悯人的融合经典与…
sympathetically marries the chassis with..."
-这个你写的 -当然是我写的
- Did you write this? - Course I wrote it.
内饰有几个小地方需要注意
"The interior would benefit from some minor attention."
-好的 它可以 -加上一颗手榴弹
- Well, it would. - With a hand grenade.
批号132
Lot number 132.
很快拍卖就开始了
Soon the auction was under way.
法拉利308GTB 十一万八成交
Ferrari 308 GTB, at £118,000.
批号127 起价三十万
Lot number 127, start me with this at 300,000.
很多竞拍者都乐于
And many of the punters were happy
为车拍出六位数
to pay six-figure sums for the cars on offer.
二十七万成交
At 270,000.
285 康塔什
285 for the Countach.
康塔什刚刚拍了285000英镑
The Countach just went for £285,000.
我认为我可以把卓越
I think I'm gonna sell The Excellent
卖出个更高的价钱
for more than that.
然后时间到了
And then it was time.
轮到了批号138A
Moving on to lot number 138A.
卓越
The Excellent.
它是一个绝妙的手工制作的
It's a fantastic handcrafted,
非常不平凡的机器  就像你看到的一样
very unusual machine, as you can see.
我不想让你…
I don't want you...
美丽又现代的梅赛德斯奔驰的车身
Beautiful, stylish Mercedes Benz coachwork.
-非常不寻常 独特 -不寻常
- Very unusual, unique... - Unusual?
在这个下午出售
Here for sale this afternoon.
起拍价 如果你们愿意
Start me if you will on this at...
425英镑
£425.
在425英镑
At £425...
有出价超过400的吗
Any advance at 400?
500磅 550磅那里
£500. 550 anywhere?
-有人在出价 -600那里
- Somebody's bid? - 600 here.
650 650 700现在
650. 650. 700 now.
我们形式很俏
We're rattling up.
700这里 700 800现在
700 here. 700. 800 now.
让我们努力争取1000
Let's go for 1,000.
让我们继续  来啊 让我们卖了这辆车
Let's get going. Come on, let's sell this car.
-1000英镑在我的右边 -你在出价
- £1,000 here on my right. - Are you bidding?
-不 -杰里米 你在出价
- No. - Jeremy, are you bidding?
2000如果你希望
2,000 if you wish.
两千五  二 五
It's 2,000 and five. Two, five.
三千现在 三千这里 三五有吗
3,000 now. It's 3,000 here. Three, five anywhere?
三 一
Three, one.
At 3,100.
£3,200.
At £3,500.
-它花了我14000 -4000
- It cost me 14,000. - 4,000.
在4000
At £4,000...
在4000 还有更多的吗
At £4,000, any more?
在4000
At £4,000.
等下过来见我们
Come and see us after.
你失去了一万块
You just lost ten grand.
他本可以把钱直接扔进厕所
He could have just thrown it down the lavatory.
它就是垃圾
It was rubbish.
等等
Hold on.
你在竞拍自己的车
- You were bidding on your own car.
好吧 只有一点点 我只是想让这势头继续
Well, a bit. I just wanted to get the ball rolling.
但是即使这样也没有用
But even then it didn't work
因为你只把它卖了四千块
because you only sold it for four grand.
做这个花了你一万四英镑
It cost you 14,000 to make
所以你花了我们出品公司一万英镑
so you cost our production company £10,000.
不不 这不对
No, no, not true.
-我订了保留价 -什么保留价
- I put a reserve on it. - What reserve?
十万英镑
£100,000.
-十万英镑 -所以它根本没有卖出去
- £100,000? - So it didn't sell at all,
也就是说你花了我们一万四千英镑
which means you cost us £14,000?
好吧 但是我们最后有了卓越
Well, yes, but we've ended up with The Excellent.
不 我们无法摆脱卓越了
No, we're stuck with The Excellent.
和你在一起工作 很难知道
It's really difficult to know, working with you,
像这样的事情 是雄心壮志
things like this, is it ambition
还是你只是个疯子
or are you a lunatic?
难过的是现在并不是回答这个问题的时间
Sadly there isn't time to answer that question,
因为是时候进入我们的明星脑碰脑
because it's time to play Celebrity Brain Crash.
我们这周的嘉宾是一个当地的女孩
Our guest this week is a local girl
为一首我历来最喜欢的流行歌
who is responsible for one of my all-time favourite pop songs,
99个红气球
99 Red Balloons.
她是一个歌手
She is a singer,
她是个腋毛爱好者
she's an armpit hair enthusiast
她是个全能运动手
and she's an all-round good sport.
女士们先生们 让我们欢迎内娜
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome Nena!
-她在哪里 -我不知道
- Where is she? - I've got no idea. Um...
哦 哦 不
Oh. Oh, no...
雾这么大很难看清
It's hard to see through the smog,
但是的 这是
but yes, that is...
-哦不 -在那里发生的是
- Oh, no. - What's happened here is...
内娜
Nena...
是的 她被99只
yes, she's been carried away by 99...
-红气球给带走  -哦不
- ...red balloons. - Oh, no.
真坏
Bad.
那就是说她不会来了 然后呢
Does that mean she's not coming on, then?
穿着 她已经飘到平流层了
Well, James, she's floated up into the stratosphere,
她的眼皮被冻掉了而且她的肺也翻出来了
her eyelids have frozen over and her lungs are inside out.
所以那是一个不
So that is a no.
不过 没关系
It's OK, though.
我们早就料到内娜会飘走
We anticipated that Nena may float away.
我们有一个备用计划 让我们激活这个 你们坐坐好
We have a back-up plan. We'll activate it. You sit down.
你看 事情是这样的 越来越多的东西
You see, the thing is... that more and more stuff,
这些日子里 靠充电电池驱动
these days, is being powered by rechargeable batteries.
你知道的 手机 笔记本 那种东西
You know, phones, laptops. That sort of thing.
这个给世界带来了一个问题
And this is giving the world a bit of a problem.
因为在英国 我们的电力公司只生产
Because in Britain, our power companies only produce
比我们所需的多5%的电力
five per cent more power than we need.
我们勉强度日
We're only just coping.
在美国这情况更糟糕
It's actually worse in the United States
因为他们生产的比他们实际所需少16%
cos they produce 16% less than they actually need,
这就意味着他们要进口电力
which means they have to import electricity.
所以当越来越多的人开始
So what is gonna happen as more and more people
购买和使用电动汽车 会发生什么呢
are buying and using electric cars?
我们会需要更多的电力 我们可能没办法应对
We're gonna need more power. We may not be able to cope.
解决方法 你可能会想
The solution, you may think,
多建几个发电厂
is to build more power stations.
但即使你仅仅只是这样建议
But if you even suggest that,
怪胡子的环保主义者就会东奔西跑
weird-beard environmentalists run around
挥着他们的手臂 说
waving their arms in the air, going,
那北极熊和蝙蝠还有蝾螈怎么办
"What about the polar bear and the bats and the newt?"
不管怎样 重点是我们需要更多更多的能源
Anyway, the point is we are going to need more and more power
来为我们手机 笔记本和车里的电池充电
to charge the batteries in our phones, laptops and cars.
-我们要从哪里得到呢 -所以这让我们开始思考
- Where are we gonna get it from? - This got us thinking.
我们一天可以产生多少电力
How much electricity could we possibly generate every day
仅仅在我们的日常生活中
just during our normal lives?
我们在某些程度上可以利用它
And what if we could harness it in some way?
这里是一座位于伦敦中心的办公大楼
This is an office block in the centre of London.
和很多办公大楼一样 它有旋转门
Like many office blocks, it has a revolving door,
随着人来人往一直旋转
which spins constantly as people come and go.
所以说 为什么不把门变成一个发电机呢
So, why not simply connect that door to a generator
把旋转的动能变成电能
and turn all that spinning into electricity?
当然 并不只有旋转门
And it's not just revolving doors, either.
我们很多人都有狗狗
Many of us have dogs
每天我们遛狗的时候
and every day we take those dogs for a walk.
狗狗蹦蹦跳跳四处乱窜
A dog scampers hither and thither, running ahead
在灌木丛下嗅来嗅去
and snouting under hedgerows.
所以说为什么不给狗狗安一个这样的拖车
So why not attach it to a trailer like this?
狗狗把小车一路拖着
Dog pulls the trailer along.
在这里轮子里是一个发电机
Inside this wheel is a dynamo.
它发的电 通过这些电线
It makes electricity, goes along these wires
流进这个电容
and into this capacitor,
当这个仪表读数达到百分之百的时候
and when that dial reads 100%,
我的手机就充上电了
I'm charging my phone,
你看 狗狗被套上了
So, dog's harnessed.
这很简单 装上拖车
That was easy. Attached to the trailer.
我要做的就是让她走起来
All I've got to do is set her going.
而且我都计划好了 看
And I've even planned for that. So, here we go.
接
Fetch!
啊哈
Ah-haa!
你最喜欢这个了
Yeah! Your favourite!
追
Chase!
这狗狗是不是坏掉了
Maybe this dog's broken?
与此同时 在伦敦
Meanwhile, back in London,
詹姆斯通过一个连接在
James was charging his phone
旋转门上的玩意儿给他的手机充电
from a contraption he'd fitted to the revolving door.
就连杰里米也想采取行动
And even Jeremy had decided to get in on the action.
学校的运动节
This school sports day,
在我的脑海里 这可是个发电厂啊
in my mind, is a power station.
我们要做的 只是给这些孩子们绑上挽具
All we have to do is fit the children with harnesses
用不了多久这个就会被充满了
and I could have this charged up in no time at all.
开始吧
Here we go!
效果立竿见影
Straightaway we can see
电流已经出现了
that charge is being produced.
不是很多 但还是有一点的
Not much, but some.
加油啊 你们加油啊
Come on, all of you! Come on!
用上后背的力量 快赶上他 加油
Put your back into it! Catch him! Chop-chop!
这主意简直是神来之笔
This is the work of a genius.
回到乡下
Back in the countryside,
我修理好了我的狗
I'd mended my dog
事情在这里也进展的不错
and things were going well here too.
正如你所见 狗狗正在跑步
As you can see, the dog is now running,
轮子也在旋转
the wheels are turning,
电力正在源源不断的产生
electricity is being generated.
他简直就是个四条腿的塞拉菲尔德核电厂嘛
He's basically a four-legged Sellafield!
难过的是 在伦敦 那是中午
Sadly, however, in London, it was the middle of the day
没人用詹姆斯的旋转门
and no one had been using James's door.
因此 他的手机快没电了
As a result, his phone was dying.
他不得已采取了非常手段
So he had to get radical.
15%.
真棒
Nice.
除了一点点小问题
Apart from a couple of hiccups...
走你
Go!
你得再努点力啊
You'll have to put a little bit more effort in than that.
一切进行的都不错
...everything was going well.
电力源源不断
The power was flooding in.
好棒
Oh, yes!
25%.
我们不得不承认
And we were forced to conclude
今天对于我们来说都是成功之日
that it had been a successful day for all of us.
额 当说出所有人的时候
Well, when I say all of us...
那个 你听我说
No. Look, listen.
我知道你为什么在这里
I can see why you're here. Um...
很明显 给孩子们绑上挽具
Obviously, fitting children with harnesses
然后拍摄他们
and then videoing them,
他们还不是我的孩子
and they're not my children...
就到这里 回帐篷去
我给我的手机冲了45%的电
I got... I got 45% charge in my phone.
我冲了41%
I got 41% charge.
我受到了另外一种电
I got a different sort of charge.
charge 有指控之意
不管怎样 自从我们已经证明了
Anyway, since we had proved...
好吧 其实是哈蒙德和我已经证明了
well, Hammond and I had proved...
可以这样给手机充电
that it was possible to charge up a telephone...
我开始好奇 我们能不能给车充电
I began to wonder if we could charge up a car
用一些几乎没有价值的东西
using nothing more than vanity.
在伦敦 有超过750家健身房
In London alone, there are over 750 gyms,
每天里面都是人
and every day they are full of people
把东西提起来再放下去
picking things up and putting them down again
所以他们可以更有吸引力
so they can be more attractive.
所以说 为什么不利用一下这巨大的能量
So why not use all this colossal effort?
让我们利用它吧
Let's harness it!
我们就是这么做的
And that's exactly what we have done.
健身房里的10台机器
Ten of the machines in this gym
都连接上了一个装置
have been connected to a device
可以产生平稳的电流
which produces a smooth flow of electricity
再输送到停车场里的G-Wiz上
that's sent outside to this G-Wiz in the car park.
现在 电池里一点电都没有
Right now the battery is flat.
我把这个插销插上
So I'm going to plug it in
8个小时之后 我们看看健身房里产生的电
and then after eight hours, we'll see how far I can drive
能让我们能把车开多远
on electricity that's been generated in there.
加油啊 你在偷懒呢
Come on, you're slacking.
8 小 时 后
好啦 从健身房断开连接
Right. Unplug from the gym.
看看我们能走多远吧
Let's see how far we go.
看啊 此刻犹如史诗般 因为我开着
Look at this. This is epic because I'm driving along
一台车 算是吧
in a car, sort of.
没有燃料被燃烧
No fossil fuel has been burned,
没有原子被裂变
and no atoms have been split.
没有什么被压裂
Nothing's been fracked up.
看哪 那里有人在推着婴儿车
Look, there's a man pushing that pushchair.
在上面装个小发电机
Stick a little dynamo on that,
孩子得到了一些新鲜空气 我则充到了更多电
kid gets some fresh air, I get more battery charge.
这样子的安排是共赢之举
It's difficult to see who loses from this arrangement.
我得以回家 基本上什么也没消耗
I get a trip home, effectively for nothing,
那些去健身房的人们感觉好 看着也好
the people going to the gym feel good, look good,
他们变得健康 NHS省了钱
they become healthier, the NHS saves money,
因为人们会更加少的
cos people are less likely
中风 你有没有
to have strokes and what have you.
如果一百个人里有一个得到了免费的健…
If one person in a hundred gets a free gy...
等等
Hang on.
我正在享受用踏板驾驶
I was enjoying driving on pedal
然后用交叉训练器发电
and cross-trainer power!
随着这个 我觉得是时候回帐篷了
And with that, I think it's back to the tent.
詹姆斯 詹姆斯梅
James... James May,
你开了多远
how far did you get
在充了8小时电以后
after eight hours of charging?
实际上 比我预期的好
Actually, it was better than I expected.
我开了34公里
I did 21 miles.
等等 从我们在伦敦的办公室
Hang on, though. To get from our office in London
到在威尔士边上额我的家
to my home in nearly Wales,
那是209公里 以34公里
that's 130 miles, 21 miles at...
所以要在健身房停六次 每次八小时
So six stops at gyms, eight hours a time,
而实际驾驶
and the actual driving,
会花去我三天
it would take me three days
才能到家
to get home!
或者 哈蒙德 只是一个想法
Or, Hammond, just an idea,
你可以买一辆汽油驱动的车
you could maybe get a petrol-powered car,
在里面加点汽油
put some petrol in it,
在两个小时里到家
and be home in two hours.
这更好 我要这么做
That's a better... I'm gonna do that.
是的 所以瞧
Yes. So there we are.
那就是未来 石油铸成的
That's the future, and it's made of petrol.
所以我们就这么愉快的决定了
So we've addressed that nicely.
继续节目
Moving on...
现在
Now...
世界各地的人们
There are people all over the world
认为我们永久地处在核战争
who believe we are permanently on the verge of nuclear war,
外星人入侵和僵尸危机的边缘
alien invasion or zombie attack.
这不是一个少数人的事
It isn't a niche thing.
有至少十二万的人
There's 120,000 of these people at least.
称自己末日族
They call themselves preppers.
-蠢货 闭嘴
- Morons. - Shut up.
-白痴 -而且这些末日族们
- Idiots. - And these preppers,
为了应对灭绝性事件
in order to prepare for an extinction-level event,
在家里囤积必需用品
stock their homes with essential supplies,
他们去森林里练习战术
they go out into the woods and practise tactics,
他们还创造了他们口中的跑路神器
and they create what they call bug-out cars.
那简直太有才了 这里有一辆 看
They're brilliant. Here is one. Look.
-看它 -是的我知道
- Look at that! - Yeah! I know!
-不 哈蒙德 这个不有才 -它就是
- No, Hammond, that is not brilliant. - It is.
你是在所我们可以将一些钉子放在现代的轮子里
Are you saying we can prepare for a nuclear attack
来预防核攻击
by putting some spikes on the wheels of a Hyundai?
如果核攻击
What if the nuclear attack
来自现代的背后呢
comes from the back of the Hyundai?
你能对这辆车做的只有
All you're gonna do with that car
-拿它来跑酷 -哦不要这么消极
- is snag your jumper on it. - Oh, don't be so negative.
在节目里你可是浪费了我们一万四千英镑
In this show you have wasted 14,000 of our pounds
在你那愚蠢的奔驰车上
on your stupid Mercedes car.
你浪费了我们所有的时间
You have wasted all of our time
在你那辆汗水驱动的电动车上
with your sweat-powered electric car.
这是我的事  让我就这么干
This is my thing. Let me do it.
你有没有认识到没有
You do realise there's no such thing
像僵尸这种东西存在 对吗
as a zombie, don't you?
不要给他戳穿了
Don't spoil it for him.
我喜欢变成末日族这个概念
I like the idea of being a prepper,
所以我觉得我要尝试做我自己的跑路神器
so I thought I'd have a go at making my own bug-out car.
这就是我的作品
This is what I came up with.
它原是一辆大众面包车 高顶版
It started life as a VW campervan, high-top version.
但我除去了它的嬉皮传统
But I've stripped it of its hippie heritage
把它变成了一辆敢于在危险的
to turn it into a vehicle that can bare its teeth
末日世界中 露出它的尖牙的车
in a dangerous, post-apocalyptic world.
而且 我很喜欢它
And I love it!
我对这辆车不能更满意了
I'm so unbelievably pleased with this thing.
我觉得自己无可匹敌 准备就绪
I feel invincible, ready, prepared.
考虑到我所做的改装
Which is hardly surprising,
这不足为奇
given the modifications I've made.
在前面 一个破城槌
At the front, a battering ram.
因为你很明确路上不会太平
You can be pretty sure the roads won't be clear.
这些槌靠钉子钉劳
The ram itself is fitted with spikes
为了在近距离抵挡僵尸
for fending off zombies at close quarters.
然后 在最顶上
Then, up top,
一组强大的聚光灯
a bank of powerful rally lights
用来穿透核冬天的黑暗
to cut through the murky soup of a nuclear winter.
当然 不是每个我见到的人都会友好
Of course, not everyone I meet will be friendly.
所以在这里
So, up here...
武器库
...weapons rack.
所有我需要的
Everything I need
在我对抗食人族和僵尸时自卫的东西
to defend myself against cannibals and zombies.
这个转角 水 必需之物
Round here, water. Essential.
还有一些微妙的事物 我可不想太引人注目
Subtle stuff too. I don't want to stand out,
所以这是伪装漆
hence the camouflage paint.
但可能是最重要的
But perhaps most importantly,
我的整辆逃跑露营车
the whole of my bug-out campervan
都武装了装甲
has been armour-plated.
我真的什么都想到了
I really have thought of everything!
不你没有
No, you haven't!
你所做的就是毁了一辆完好的露营车
All you've done is ruined a perfectly good campervan.
不 我才没有 这很有才
No, I haven't! It's brilliant.
它周身都是防弹的
It's bullet-proof all over!
-防弹的 是吗 -是的
- Bullet-proof? Is it? - Yes.
-是吗 -是的
- Is it? - Yes, it is.
-哦听上去像是 -坦克般的感觉
- Oh, yeah, sounds like it. - Tanks feel like that.
好吧 这些枪 用它们
OK, then, these are guns. Use them.
-什么 朝你 -不 朝车 射它
- What, on you? - No, on the van. Shoot it.
-我们准备好了嘛先生们 -好了
- Are we ready, gentlemen? - Yes.
哈 没有穿透
Ha! Didn't go through!
只削下了块漆 你也只能做到这样了
Just chipped the paint. That's all you've done.
-是的 哈蒙德 -怎么
- Yes. Hammond? - Yeah?
你所表达的是这些外星人
What you're suggesting is these aliens,
它们旅行了数万亿英里
they're going to travel trillions of miles
用一个我们想都不敢想的推进系统
using a propulsion system that we can't even conceive
然后他们试图控制这个世界
and then they're going to try and take over the world
用177步枪
using .177 air rifles?
好吧如果他们这样 我应该准备好了
Well, if they do, I shall be ready for them.
特别考虑到我在这里所做的一切
Especially given what I've done in here.
在内部 我把这个曾经简陋的露营车
Inside, I've turned this once-humble campervan
变成了可以想象到的最高科技控制中心
into literally the highest-tech command centre imaginable.
在前面 二氧化碳洗涤塔
Up front, carbon dioxide scrubbers,
就像在阿波罗13上的那个
just like the ones on Apollo 13.
它们可以净化空气 甚至辐射
They will purify the air, even in case of radiation.
而且你可以测量辐射 在这里的这个机器上
And you can measure that radiation on these systems up here.
水 你可能找不到它
Water. You may not be able to find it.
需要制造水 这很必须
Need to make it. It's essential.
我安装了一个系统可以回收尿液
I've fitted a system that recycles urine.
基本上你在那里小号
Basically you do your number ones up there.
操作泵
Operate the pumps.
它们将结果输送上去
They send the results up,
进入净水系统
across, and into the water purification system.
那里浮现的就会使最纯净的饮用水
It emerges from that as purest drinking water.
食物 我会需要的 我有一只鸡
Food. I'm gonna need it. I've got a chicken.
它下单 它们滚到那里
It lays eggs. They go in there.
而且可能是最好的 鹅肝酱
And perhaps best of all, the pâté de foie gras
在逃跑神器小社区
of the bug-out community...
鸡汤
chicken soup.
我喜欢这一切 启程去往荒野
I love all this. Setting out into the wilderness
用我这装了轮子的小小房子
in my little house on wheels,
知道无论发生什么 我都有所有需要的东西
knowing I've got everything I need, whatever happens.
什么鬼
What the...?
我穿透了它的防弹装甲了吗
Am I penetrating his bulletproof armour?
是的 还有他的吃的
Yes. And his food.
哦 那是我的尿
Oh! That's my own urine!
-是你们两个做的吗 -是的就是他
- Are you two doing this? - Yes, he is!
如果我是你我就会让开
I'd get out of the way if I were you.
那只鸡的问题是它老是动
The trouble with the chicken is, it moves around,
让这个变的有点…
making this a...
-哦好主意 -难道不是吗
- Oh, good idea! - Isn't it!
好吧 装弹中 船长  装弹中
Right, reloading, James. Reloading.
哦好的
Oh, yes!
-好枪法 -还不坏 不是吗
- Good shot. - Not bad, was it?
胜负已经定了 真的
Sort of game over now, really.
嗯
Hm.
好吧
Right...
其实游戏还没结束呢
It wasn't game over, though,
因为我又回到工作台前
because I went back to the drawing board
开始干活了
and started again.
三个月努力的成果
Three months' work.
我还是延用了一样的内饰设计
I've used the same basic interior set-up,
不过我完全重构了装甲镀层
but I've completely re-thought the armour plating,
所以说无论他俩上什么家伙
so that whatever those two have...
现在 弯刀轻型侦查坦克登场
Now, this is a Scimitar light reconnaissance tank.
该坦克型号小速度快 而且机动性强
It's small, it's quite fast, and it's quite manoeuvrable.
他的职责就是像山羊一样环游整个战场
Its job is to skip around the battlefield like a goat
并且找到目标
and find stuff.
看看哈蒙德 惊慌失措的疯狂逃命
Now, look at Hammond, running around in a mad panic.
他觉得我要打他 但是我并不会
He thinks I'm gonna shoot him, but I'm not.
我只在这用激光来给他定位
I'm just here to mark him with a laser.
他才是开火的那位
He's gonna shoot him.
对 这是辆挑战者2型主战坦克
Yes, this is a Challenger 2 main battle tank.
并且这绝对是一辆跑路神器
And this really is a bug-out vehicle.
它绝对要比 我也不了解
It's certainly a lot better than, I don't know,
轮子上有尖刺的现代要厉害很多
a Hyundai with spikes on the wheels.
它能够保护它的雇主们防御
It'll totally protect its occupants from radiation,
辐射 核放射性沉降 毒气
nuclear fallout, gas,
由于它强大的护甲 甚至还能防御住任何
even a direct hit, thanks to its incredible armour,
战场武器的迎面一击
from any known battlefield weapon.
然后这个就是大炮了
Then there's this gun, which is...
没什么别的可以形容它了 巨大无比
there's no other word... enormous!
120毫米口径
120mm.
并且它能击中任何目标
And it could hit a target...
就拿理查德哈蒙德的面包车来说
let's say Richard Hammond's van...
期间还保持着48KM/H的速度在颠簸路面上行驶
while the tank itself is doing 30mph over rough ground.
然而 今天我打算静止的时候开火
I think, though, today I shall fire while stationary
因为我想好好品味一下这个瞬间
because I want to savour the moment.
好的 谢啦 兄弟们 我们就停这吧
OK, thank you, chaps. If we could stop there...
好的 到驾驶席去
Right, going down.
收到 去驾驶席
Roger. Going down.
哎呦我操
Oh, dear!
我装了一发高爆弹
I've loaded the gun with a high-explosive shell.
这是个曳光弹 所以我们能
It's a tracer shell, so we'll be able
在炮弹击中目标的时候
to monitor its progress
看到它的轨迹
as it arcs toward the target.
克拉克森指挥官 这想法棒极了
Oh, Commander Clarkson, this is fantastic!
我能从这里看见他 你找到他了吗
I can see him right there. Have you got him?
是的
Yeah.
一群混蛋
You bastards!
直接让他从痛苦中解脱出来吧 好不好
Oh, just put him out of his misery, will you?
开火
Fire!
我不太确信他的跑路工具
I'm not sure his bug-out vehicle was quite as strong
能像他让你们深信不疑的那样坚固
as he may have led you to believe.
好吧
Right...
好几个月以后
Many months later,
我已经准备好发布我第三次尝试
I was ready to unveil my third attempt...
一辆固若金汤的堡垒
...an impregnable fortress.
这才是跑路天堂
This is bug-out heaven!
我可用尽了我的灵感
I've used as my inspiration
装甲可是外星科技
the armoured personnel carrier from Aliens,
照理来讲能把西格妮韦弗
on the basis that if it can protect Sigourney Weaver
武装到牙齿
from that metal bitey thing with teeth,
它能保护我防御杰里米和詹姆斯的攻击
it can keep me safe from Jeremy Clarkson and James May.
这车以Alvis Stalwart军卡为基础
Underneath this beast are the basic elements of an Alvis Stalwart.
所以已经有装甲 还水陆两栖
So it was already armour-plated, amphibious,
动力巨大
massively powerful,
六轮驱动 四轮转向
six-wheel drive and four-wheel steering.
而我所作的 就是改进它
And what I've gone and done is improve it.
它有蜂巢结构的
It's got a honeycombed lattice work
钢陶装甲
of ceramic-steel armour plating.
比你能在A1M1坦克上找到的装甲
It's three times thicker than the armour you'll find
还要厚3倍
on the turret of an Abrams A1M1 tank.
为了测试 我对外壳打了发7.62毫米的
In testing, I fired a 7.62 round at that hull,
而它只留下这么一个印子
and all it left was a mark like that one.
这货太厉害了
This thing is incredible.
不管那俩这次打什么歪主意
Whatever those two are planning this time,
都没用
it won't work.
他们可坏不了我的汤了
They won't be able to damage my soup now.
无人机反馈稳定
Drone feed stabilised.
开阔地带发现车辆
Vehicle spotted in the open.
45号舰准备截获目标
45 stand by to engage target.
45号舰已截获目标
45 stood to engage target.
这炮弹 比我们从坦克里打的那发
This shell... is twice as powerful
威力要大2倍
as the shell we fired from the tank.
它能打击20公里的目标
And it can hit a target 13 miles away.
装填弹药
Loading weapon.
指挥室 弹药已装填 准备完毕
Hot room, gun loaded. Gun ready.
执行开火程序
Fire mission,
目标编号 UT 1805
target number Uniform Tango 1805.
海拔35
Altitude 35.
距离 4600
Direction 4600.
炮目线 方位130 高低角68
Gun target line 130. Ready 68.
同意发射
Command approve.
45号舰 准备干预
45. Engage.
批准发射 45号舰 发射
Command approve. 45. Fire.
他们觉得无聊了 发现我无法伤害
They're bored. They've realised I'm unhurtable...
就放弃了
...and given up.
5秒命中目标
Five seconds to impact.
他们可能觉得这很有趣
They probably think it's really funny.
他们还以为我在外面
They probably think I'm out here all...
45 目标摧毁
45. Target destroyed.
好了
Now,
后来我们去残骸看了一圈
we went through the wreckage afterwards
这就是哈蒙德的遗骸了
and this is all that remains of Richard Hammond.
他化成灰了 但我们知道就是他
He's just dust, and we know it is Hammond
因为我们找到了颗
because we found this suspiciously white tooth...
白得出奇的牙齿
...in it. That's...
-就是他 -没错了
- That's him. - That's him.
所以 末日族们 你们看
So, there you are, preppers.
哈蒙德悲壮的遗骸告诉我们
The tragic remains of Richard Hammond are proof positive
你们的爱好是完全没意义的
that your hobby is utterly pointless.
-你把他撒了 -把他洒向地板
- You spilled him! - Spilt him on the floor.
你把他弄在鞋上了
Now you've got him all over your shoes.
我知道 他就算化成灰都那么讨厌
I know. Even when he's dust, he's annoying.
不管了
Anyway...
伴随着这可怕的失望之情
On that terrible disappointment,
是结束的时候了
it is time to end.
应该把他弄走了
He's pretty much gone now.
感谢您的收看
Thank you very much for watching.
下次再见
See you next time. Goodbye!